# ETHAN ESCARENO

Sr. Frontend Engineer

#### **DETAILS**

#### **ADDRESS**

Playa del Carmen Mexico

#### **PHONE**

+528991053009

#### **EMAIL**

ethan.rosanoo@gmail.com

#### LINKS

https://github.com/ethaan

### **SKILLS**

Javascript

Typescript

HTML

React

React Native

Git

CSS

MUI

**TailwindCSS** 

Next.js

AWS

**Testing Frameworks** 

#### **PROFILE**

Software Engineer with +8 years of experience in the development world, working on startups and small to medium companies. Have worked in teams where everybody has to wear multiple hats. Currently seeking for a job where I can keep learning and making use of new technologies.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Sr. Frontend Engineer, Mora Medical

Costa Mesa (Remote)

Aug 2022 - Present

- Led and develop different features and assets that helped increase customer acquisition
- Built a Mobile Application using react native app (https://apps.apple.com/mx/app/mora-medical/id1673784047) for Patient acquisition and Patient retention.
- Replaced Google forms with custom in-house forms to on board new customers, for example:
  - https://onboardings.mora.com
  - https://yashoda.mora.com/assessment
- Developed a CMS from scratch used by medical personal using TailiwindCSS, NextJS and Supabase to increase productivity and automation.
- Active participation on day to day business operations.

## Lead Frontend Engineer, Sapien Network Brooklyn (Remote) May 2020 – Aug 2022

- Led the frontend team to develop the v3 of the app using NextJS with TailwindCSS
- Set a branching strategy to be used in all our repos to keep things clean and organized.
- Collaborated with backend team on the creation new of API endpoints
- Built a flow to buy, claim, and customize NFT's making use of web3 libraries
- Developed a system to post, comment, vote content and chat (Discord/Reddit Clone for Web3)
- Mentored other engineers

Jan 2018 - Mar 2020

- Led 10+ features, one of them helped to win a 1 million deal with California campuses
- Migrated a 4yo code from Jest+Enzyme to Jest+RTL
- Important focus on keeping the codebase up to date with the best practices
- Big Focus on A11y
- Implemented Github actions to replace in-house Jenkins setup for better reliability
- Switched from Redux to React hooks and migrated away from Class Components completly
- Took various workshops and courses given by the company as part of continuous learning

#### Frontend Engineer, Edthena

San Francisco (Remote)

Feb 2016 - Nov 2017

- Migrated the frontend from MeteorJs to VueJs by first creating a library of components, making use of Storybook to test and iterate over ideas
- Migrated the landing page from Ruby to simple HTML/JS/CSS Add to improve developer experience
- Collaboration with CTO and Lead Engineer for feature completition.

## **EDUCATION**

IT Bachelor's, UTTN

2015